Hi everybody.
Hyundai is one of
the most iconic
companies to enter
the indian markets.
It is hard to
believe that a south
korean brand, which
was once a difficult
name to pronounce,
is today about to
launch the biggest
ipo in the history
of India. Indian
stock markets could
soon see their
biggest ever ipo.
South korean
automaker Hyundai is
gearing up for a
significant
milestone by going
public in India.
Hyundai's ipo is
poised to be one of
the largest in
recent times,
potentially the
biggest ipo ever in
India. This would be
India's largest ipo
and the first ven
automaker since
Maruti Suzuki in
2003. In 1996,
when Hyundai entered
the indian market,
Maridi was the most
dominant player with
a 60% market share,
almost a monopoly
amongst the middle
class in India.
Despite this,
Hyundai came in with
models like Santro,
I ten, I 20 and
Krita making a
significant impact.
Today, Hyundai is
the second largest
automaker in the
country with a
profit of 4653
crores. In terms of
profitability,
Hyundai is way ahead
of Maruti in FY two
three. While Hyundai
made a profit of
rs65,355 per
vehicle, Maruti made
a profit of rs4939
per vehicle. Now,
after 28 years of
establishing a
stronghold in the
indian market,
Hyundai plans to
raise 25,000 crores
with its ipo.
Sounds fantastic,
right? However,
there are some
hidden risks that
Hyundai faces which
may jeopardize all
the progress they've
made in India. All
of this is detailed
in a 436 page dear
HP paper that
Hyundai filed with S
EbI. We've gone
through all this
data so that you can
sit back and consume
the most important
bits of this 400
page document as
easily as watching a
movie. In this
episode, let's dive
into understanding
how a south korean
company like Hyundai
broke into the
indian automobile
market, leaving
behind giants like
Tata and Mahindra.
Despite being a
foreign company,
how did Hyundai
achieve such high
profitability and
outpace a mammoth
like Maruti in
India? Most
importantly, after
making such amazing
progress, what are
the hidden risks
that could topple
Hyundai's growth in
India? Also, a quick
disclaimer. I am not
a SEBI registered
investment advisor
and this video is
not meant to give
you investment
advice, but to only
educate you about
the rise of Hyundai
in India. Before we
move on, I want to
quickly introduce
you to our education
partners of today's
episode Scalar
School of Business.
They are bringing
something absolutely
revolutionary. If
you're seeking
business education,
Scaler is offering a
full time, on campus
18 month pg program
in management and
technology. This
program is designed
by leaders who have
built billion dollar
businesses like
Uber, MNCHA and
Meesho. Today,
legacy college names
are useless without
competitive skill
sets. This is why as
part of the Scalar
School of Business
curriculum, you will
work on real world
projects sourced
from real companies.
You will build your
own business, take
it to the market,
generate revenue and
raise vc capital
while studying on
campus. Since dealer
has been in the
education industry
for seven long
years, they already
have access to 1200
company partners,
something no other b
school in the
country can offer.
Right now. For their
online programs,
they've seen
placement rates of
96% with a median
CTC of 25 lakh
rupees verified by
BDK analytics, the
same partner that
verifies reports for
IMIs. Now Scalar
School of Business
is handpicking only
75 students for
their founding
cohort starting in
August 2024. They
have scholarships up
to 100% and
applications are
open right now. If
you want to become a
brilliant business
leader, apply for
scalar School of
Business using the
link in my
description and in
the comment section.
Now on with the
episode. The first
thing you need to
understand about a
company is their
philosophy of
success. In this
case, you need to
understand what
exactly is the
philosophy that
turned Hyundai into
what it is today in
India. Like we saw
in the Boeing video,
no matter how much
profitability,
EBITDA or earnings
per share a company
has, if it deviates
from its core
philosophy, all
these numbers will
go for a toss. So
lets understand the
core philosophy and
then move on to
profitability,
EBITDA and other
numbers. Now the
question is what
exactly is the
secret recipe for
Hyundais success in
India? This story
dates back to the
early 1990s. Until
this point, India
only had a few car
brands, Hindustan,
Ambassador,
Contessa, Premier,
Padmini, Standard
Herald 2000, Maridi
800, Omni and Gypsy.